Diane Wolkstein collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Diane Wolkstein collection 1960-2013 1967-2012
AFC 2016/057
Wolkstein, Diane
approximately 13,526 items
approximately 6,838 documents
274 sound cassettes: analog
7 sound cassettes (DAT): digital
7 sound tape reels: analog; 5 in.
6 sound tape reels: analog; 7 in.
6 sound tape reels: analog; 10 in.
244 sound discs (CD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
371 sound files (WAV, AIFF): digital
658 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 35 mm
20 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 4x5 in.
13 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 120 mm
9 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 126 film
4 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 8x10 in.
313 photographs: film negatives, color; 35 mm
62 photographs: film negatives, color; 126 film
2 photographs: film negatives, color; 4x5 in.
2 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm
514 photographs: prints, color; various sizes
338 photographs: prints, black and white; various sizes
50 photographs: contact sheets, black and white; various sizes
2,152 photographs: digital: JPG, PSD
204 videocassettes (MiniDV): analog
82 videocassettes (VHS): analog
34 videocassettes (Hi8): analog
7 videocassettes (VHS-C): analog
5 videocassettes (U-matic): analog
4 videocassettes (DVCam): analog
4 open reel video tape: analog; 1/2 in.
2 videocassettes (BetacamSP): analog
2 film reel: analog; 16 mm
145 videodiscs (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
1,147 video files (IFO, BUP, VOB, MOV, MP4, MPG): digital
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Performance recordings, publicity, story drafts, photographs, and research files comprising the professional archive of storyteller Diane Wolkstein.
Provenance
Diane Wolkstein estate, Purchase, 2016; Rachel Zucker, Donation, 2024.
Accruals
No further accruals expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Diane Wolkstein collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Diane Wolkstein was a storyteller, author, and folklorist. Born in 1942, she received an undergraduate degree from Smith College, a master's degree in education from Bank Street College of New York, and studied mime under Etienne Decroux in Paris. She worked as New York City's official storyteller between 1967 and 1971 and later worked as a freelance storyteller. She performed stories for children every weekend in Central Park at the Hans Christian Andersen statue and hosted the radio show Stories from Many Lands on WNYC from 1968 to 1980. Wolkstein also traveled extensively to conduct fieldwork, gathering myths, stories, and songs to adapt and include in her storytelling. She was the author of two dozen books. Diane Wolkstein passed away in 2013 in Kaohsiung, Taiwan, while conducting research for a book of Chinese folk stories.
Scope and Content
Papers and audiovisual materials comprising the professional archive of storyteller Diane Wolkstein. Includes performance events and productions, publicity materials, fieldwork interviews, publishing contracts, correspondence, field notes, and story drafts.
Wolkstein adapted folktales from many cultures for performance and publication, producing stories for both adults and children. The collection includes her recordings and notes from research in Haiti, China, Australia, and other locations, used to inform her stories. Also included in the collection are recordings of Wolkstein's radio program Stories from Many Lands, which ran from 1968 to 1980 on WNYC radio. In 2007, Wolkstein produced a documentary about her life and work entitled A Storyteller's Story. Materials used to produce the documentary are included as a part of the collection.
Arrangement
The Diane Wolkstein collection is organized in 8 series:
Series 1: Story research (1970-2012)
Series 2: Story drafts (1972-2010)
Series 3: Story performances (1960-2012, bulk: 1967-2012)
Series 4: WNYC Stories From Many Lands Radio Show (1967-1980)
Series 5: Marketing and publicity (1960-2011, bulk: 1968-2007)
Series 6: Administrative files (1969-2012)
Series 7: Workshops and teaching (1970-2012, bulk: 1981-2006)
Series 8: A Storyteller's Story documentary production files (1995-2007)
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Baker, Augusta, 1911-1998--Interviews.; Belpré, Pura--Interviews.; Bodger, Joan--Interviews.; Carlebach, Shlomo, 1925-1994; Courlander, Harold, 1908-1996; Dodge, Marshall, 1935-1982--Interviews.; Kramer, Samuel Noah, 1897-1990; McLendon, Sally--Interviews.; Singer, Isaac Bashevis, 1904-1991--Interviews.; Smith, Jimmy Neil--Interviews.; Sutton-Smith, Brian--Interviews.; Timpanelli, Gioia--Interviews.; Wheeler, Billy Edd; Wolkstein, Diane, collector, creator.; Wolkstein, Diane--Archives.; Zucker, Rachel
Organizations
WNYC (Radio station: New York, N.Y.)
Subjects
Children's literature.; Fairy tales.; Folklore--Australia.; Folklore--China.; Folklore--Egypt.; Folklore--Haiti.; Folklore--United States.; Jewish children's stories.; Jews--Folklore.; Storytellers--United States.; Storytelling.; Sumerian literature.; Tales.; Women folklorists--United States.; Women storytellers--New York (State)--New York.
Form/Genre
Correspondence.; Folk tales.; Interviews.; Manuscripts.; Radio programs.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Story research
  Field notes, correspondence, audio recordings, and photographs created by Diane Wolkstein when she conducted research to write stories. Fieldwork locations include Haiti, Egypt, China, Taiwan, India, and Greece.
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts and Photographic Prints
    Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - China research notebook, July 2009, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/1)
    - China research trips, 1988-1998, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Egypt research trip, circa 1984, 1 folder of manuscripts with 4 color photographic prints (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Egypt travel notebook, 1983-1984, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 18/1)
    - The Grass Slipper research, China, 1998, 1 folder of manuscripts with 64 color photographic prints (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Haiti correspondence, 1973-1976, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Haiti interview questions, circa 1973, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Haiti research notebook (1 of 2), circa 1973, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Haiti research notebook (2 of 2), circa 1973, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Haitian songs, 1976, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Haiti photos, circa 1970s, afc2016057_dc310; Likely digital copies of analog photographs.; 26 color photographs (JPG)
    - Haiti photos, circa 1970s, afc2016057_dc312; Likely digital copies of analog photographs.; 16 black-and-white and color photographs (JPG)
    - Haiti photos, 1973, 28 black-and-white photographic prints and 30 color photographic prints (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Haiti photos, circa 1974-1976, afc2016057_dc408; Video compilation of digital copies of analog photographs taken by Shirley Keller; 11 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Haiti photos, 1976, afc2016057_dc324; Video of slide show of analog slides; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - I Ching research notebook, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Inanna research notebook, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts with 1 color photographic print (Box-folder 1/11)
    - India photographs, circa 2008, afc2016057_dc124; 18 color photographs (JPG, PSD)
    - Ireland, Scotland, and England research notebook, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Jewish teachings research notebook, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Journey to the West research notebook, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Monkey King photographs, circa 2001, afc2016057_dc126; 8 color photographs (JPG)
    - Monkey King photograph, circa 2009, afc2016057_dc128; 1 color photograph (JPG)
    - Monkey King research notebooks (1 of 4), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Monkey King research notebooks (2 of 4), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Monkey King research notebooks (3 of 4), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Monkey King research notebooks (4 of 4), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Myth research notebook, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Research notebooks (1 of 2), circa 1988, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Research notebooks (2 of 2), circa 1988, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Research notebook, 1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Research notebook, 1991, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Research notebook, 1996, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Research notebook, circa 1990s, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Research notebook, circa 2010-2012, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Research notebooks (1 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Research notebooks (2 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Research notebooks (3 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Research notebooks (4 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Research notebooks (5 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Research notebooks (6 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Research notebooks (7 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Research notebooks (8 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Research notebooks (9 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Research notebooks (10 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Research notebooks (11 of 11), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Taiwan research notebook, January-February 2010, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Taiwan research notebook, January-March 2010, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Taoism research notebook, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Torah research notebook, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Subseries 2: Slides and Negatives
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Haiti storytellers, April 1973, 9 black-and-white negatives (126 film); 5 color negatives (126 film); AFC 2016/057: PH210 (Box 25, Box 26)
    - Cortes Caille Marson Bonheur, Haiti, 1973, 57 color negatives (126 film); 6 black-and-white negatives (120mm); AFC 2016/057: PH208 (Box 26, Box 25)
    - Cortes Caille Iona, Croix des Missions, Caille Marson Bonheur, Haiti, 1973, 7 black-and-white negatives (120mm); AFC 2016/057: PH209 (Box 25)
    - The Grass Slipper research, China, 1998, 96 color slides; AFC 2016/057: PH014 - PH109 (Box 23)
    - China photographs, undated, 45 color negatives (35mm); AFC 2016/057: PH253 (Box 26)
    - Egypt photographs, undated, 8 color negatives (35mm); AFC 2016/057: PH211 (Box 26)
    - Egypt photographs, undated, 1 color slide; AFC 2016/057: PH212 (Box 23)
    - Egypt and Greece photographs, undated, 87 color negatives (35mm); AFC 2016/057: PH251 (Box 26)
    - Inanna research photographs, undated, 7 black-and-white negatives (4x5 in.); AFC 2016/057: PH198 (Box 25)
    - Inanna research photographs, undated, 3 black-and-white negatives (4x5 in.); AFC 2016/057: PH200 (Box 25)
    - Inanna research photographs, undated, 88 color slides; AFC 2016/057: PH110 - PH197 (Box 23)
    - India photographs, undated, 38 color slides; AFC 2016/057: PH254 to PH291 (Box 23)
    - Priene, Greece photographs, undated, 35 color negatives (35mm); AFC 2016/057: PH292 (Box 26)
  - Subseries 3: Audio and Video
    Arranged alphabetically by carrier title. Duplicate content may exist throughout. The archivist has paired associated content together when possible.
    - China, 2009
      - Part 1 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV001; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 1 - DVD, afc2016057_dc387; Chang An; Taoist; Xian; Storyteller; White Horse; Storyteller; Loman Caves; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
      - Part 2 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV002; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2 - DVD, afc2016057_dc388; Cold Mountain; Potosan; Yellow Mountain; Quan Yin; Ming Hai Interview; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
      - Part 3 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV004; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 4 - DVD, afc2016057_dc386; Mountains: Mosque; Xian; Monkey King conversation with interesting woman; Qin; Wild Goose pagoda; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Chinese Music, September 16, 1977, AFC 2016/057: SR001; 1 sound cassette
    - Course with Mr. Sun, undated, afc2016057_dc151; 12 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Diane in Taipei - Jeremy, August 18-19, 2008
      - Part 1 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV005; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 1 - DVD, afc2016057_dc153; 10 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
      - Part 2 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV006; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2 - DVD, afc2016057_dc142; 10 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
      - Part 3 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV007; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 3 - DVD, afc2016057_dc140; 10 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
      - Part 4 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV008; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 4 - DVD, afc2016057_dc145; 10 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
      - Part 5 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV009; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 5 - DVD, afc2016057_dc130; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
      - Part 6 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV010; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 6 - DVD, afc2016057_dc141; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Dr. Kramer, May 9, 1987
      - Part 1 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV011; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 1 - DVD, afc2016057_dc056; 7 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
      - Part 2 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV012; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2 - DVD, afc2016057_dc041; 7 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Egypt, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR003; 1 sound cassette
    - Eli Chayim's Hallel, April 1987, AFC 2016/057: SR004; 1 sound cassette
    - Estonian Folk melodies played on the Estonian folk instrument kannel by Lilian Esop, October 18, 1975, AFC 2016/057: SR005; 1 sound tape reel: 5 in.
    - Estonian Folksongs, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR006; 1 sound tape reel: 5 in.
    - Flinders Island - Lawlor/Lambert, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV013; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Folklore d' Haiti, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR007; 1 sound cassette
    - Haiti - introduction, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR008; 1 sound cassette
    - Haitian histories, music, and stories, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR009; 1 sound cassette
    - Haitian melodies from The Magic Orange Trees stories, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR010; 1 sound cassette
    - Haitian Stories, Recordings of songs and stories collected during Diane Wolkstein's fieldwork in Haiti
      - Part 1, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR011; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 1A, March 21, 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR012; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 1A, 1B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR013; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 1B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR014; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 2, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR015; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 2A, 2B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR016; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 2A, 1A, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR017; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 2A, 3A, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR018; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 3, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR019; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 3, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR020; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 3A, 3B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR021; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 3B, 4A, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR022; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 4, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR023; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 4, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR024; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 4B, 5B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR025; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 5, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR026; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 5, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR027; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 6, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR028; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 6, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR029; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 6A, 6B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR030; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 7, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR031; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 7, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR032; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 7A, 7B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR033; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 8, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR034; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 8, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR035; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 8A, 8B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR036; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 9, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR037; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 10, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR038; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 11, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR039; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 11, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR040; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 11A, 11B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR041; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 12, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR042; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 12, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR043; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 12A, 12B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR044; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 13, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR045; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 13A, 13AA, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR046; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 13A, 13AA, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR047; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 13B, 13BB, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR048; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 14, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR049; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 14, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR050; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 14A, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR051; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 14A, 14B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR052; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 14BB, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR053; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 15, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR054; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 16, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR055; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 17, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR056; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 18A, 18B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR057; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 20A, 20B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR058; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 21A, 21B, circa 1973, AFC 2016/057: SR059; 1 sound cassette
    - Harold Courlander interview, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR060; 1 sound cassette
    - Howard Schwarz, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR061; 1 sound cassette
    - "How to Tell a Story" conception tape, December 5, 1990, AFC 2016/057: MV003; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - IB Singer #2, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR062; 1 sound cassette
    - Ideas for the future, February 20, 1996, AFC 2016/057: MV199; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - India footage, October 27-28, 2008, afc2016057_dc121; 8 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Ireland - Irish Harp and Songs, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR063; 1 sound cassette
    - Japanese stories, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR064; 1 sound cassette
    - Japanese stories, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR065; 1 sound cassette
    - Jeanne Philippe - commentary, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR066; 1 sound cassette
    - Joan Bodger, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV014; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Joan Bodger on CBC Radio One: This Morning Tonight, May 14, 1998, AFC 2016/057: SR067; 1 sound cassette
    - John Miles Foley, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR068; 1 sound cassette
    - Journey East documentary, undated, afc2016057_dc360; Documentary video created by Diane Wolkstein about her 2008 trip to Taiwan to research the Monkey King story.; 7 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Latin American Folk Tales, Suni Paz, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR069; 1 sound cassette
    - Learning Rosh Hashana - Part 1, August 29, 1991, AFC 2016/057: SR070; 1 sound cassette
    - Lecture: Adam in Garden, Rabbi Kurzver, October 1, 1989, AFC 2016/057: SR071; 1 sound cassette
    - Maid Marlene, May 2, 1999, AFC 2016/057: SR072; 1 sound cassette
    - Monkey King mythology group, November 21, 2009
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: MV206; 1 videocassette (VHS)
      - Part 2, November 21, 2009, AFC 2016/057: MV207; 1 videocassette (VHS)
      - Part 3, November 21, 2009, AFC 2016/057: MV208; 1 videocassette (VHS)
    - Niggun, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR073; 1 sound cassette
    - Out bush with Latzie, January 1996, AFC 2016/057: MV283; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
    - Person to Person, Joan Bodger interview, 2001, AFC 2016/057: MV284; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
    - Philip Adams interview, November 23, 1995, AFC 2016/057: SR074; 1 sound cassette
    - Rock Painting Quincon - Steve Treuze, December 13, 1995, AFC 2016/057: MV285; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
    - Santa Teresa summarizing - singing, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV286; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
    - Shlomo Carlebach, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR075; 1 sound cassette
    - Shlomo Carlebach, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR076; 1 sound cassette
    - Shlomo's Shabbat, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR077; 1 sound cassette
    - The Silk Drum, The Dead Seal River, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR088; 1 sound cassette
    - Singer interview, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR078; 1 sound cassette
    - Some ideas of what is being done, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV287; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
    - Sumerians I: Kramer, Queen and Shepherd: Sumerian Tales, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR080; 1 sound cassette
    - Sumerians II: Fulco, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR081; 1 sound cassette
    - Sumerians 2: Kramer, Development of Cuneiform, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR082; 1 sound cassette
    - Sumerians 7: Inanna and Huluppu-Tree, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR083; 1 sound cassette
    - Suzanne Stasz interview, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR084; 1 sound tape (7-inch)
    - Taiwan, August 13, 2008
      - Part 1 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV324; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
      - Part 1 - DVD, afc2016057_dc143; 10 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
      - Part 2 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV325; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
      - Part 2 - DVD, afc2016057_dc144; 10 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Taiwan trip, August 2008, afc2016057_dc152; 11 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Talking Yom Kippur, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR085; 1 sound cassette
    - Ted Carpenter, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR086; 1 sound cassette
    - Ted Carpenter, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR087; 1 sound cassette
    - Traditional Songs, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR089; 1 sound cassette
    - Uluru, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV338; 1 videocassette (VHS)
    - Uluru, Diane Wolkstein's trip to Australia, 1996, AFC 2016/057: MV344; 1 videocassette (VHS)
    - Yom Kippur, 1990, AFC 2016/057: SR090; 1 sound cassette
    - Yom Kippur, 1990, AFC 2016/057: SR091; 1 sound cassette
    - Yom Kippur - Neila, 1990, AFC 2016/057: SR092; 1 sound cassette
- Series 2: Story Drafts
  Drafts of Wolkstein's published and unpublished stories at various stages of development. Also includes original drafts of cover art and illustrations for some of Wolkstein's published works.
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts and Photographic Prints
    - Abulafia Dream Songs drafts, 1991, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Abulafia Dream Songs drafts, 1992, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Abulafia Dream Songs drafts, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Australian folktales book proposal, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Biblical stories drafts, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/3)
    - Bracelets draft, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/5)
    - The Cool Ride in the Sky drafts, 1972, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/6)